<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecosystem on Paimon文档</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecosystem on Paimon文档</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh</language>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/ecosystem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/overview/</guid>
      <description>Overview&#xD;#&#xD;Compatibility Matrix&#xD;#&#xD;Engine Version Batch Read Batch Write Create Table Alter Table Streaming Write Streaming Read Batch Overwrite DELETE &amp;amp; UPDATE MERGE INTO Time Travel Flink 1.15 - 1.20 ✅ ✅ ✅ ✅(1.17+) ✅ ✅ ✅ ✅(1.17+) ❌ ✅ Spark 3.2 - 3.5 ✅ ✅ ✅ ✅ ✅(3.3+) ✅(3.3+) ✅ ✅ ✅ ✅(3.3+) Hive 2.1 - 3.1 ✅ ✅ ✅ ❌ ❌ ❌ ❌ ❌ ❌ ✅ Trino 420 - 440 ✅ ✅(427+) ✅(427+) ✅(427+) ❌ ❌ ❌ ❌ ❌ ✅ Presto 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StarRocks</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/starrocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/starrocks/</guid>
      <description>StarRocks&#xD;#&#xD;This documentation is a guide for using Paimon in StarRocks.&#xA;Version&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon currently supports StarRocks 3.1 and above. Recommended version is StarRocks 3.2.6 or above.&#xA;Create Paimon Catalog&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon catalogs are registered by executing a CREATE EXTERNAL CATALOG SQL in StarRocks. For example, you can use the following SQL to create a Paimon catalog named paimon_catalog.&#xA;CREATE EXTERNAL CATALOG paimon_catalog PROPERTIES( &amp;#34;type&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;paimon&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;paimon.catalog.type&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;filesystem&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;paimon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doris</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/doris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/doris/</guid>
      <description>Doris&#xD;#&#xD;This documentation is a guide for using Paimon in Doris.&#xA;More details can be found in Apache Doris Website&#xA;Version&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon currently supports Apache Doris 2.0.6 and above.&#xA;Create Paimon Catalog&#xD;#&#xD;Use CREATE CATALOG statement in Apache Doris to create Paimon Catalog.&#xA;Doris support multi types of Paimon Catalogs. Here are some examples:&#xA;-- HDFS based Paimon Catalog CREATE CATALOG `paimon_hdfs` PROPERTIES ( &amp;#34;type&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;paimon&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;warehouse&amp;#34; = &amp;#34;hdfs://172.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hive</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/hive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/hive/</guid>
      <description>Hive&#xD;#&#xD;This documentation is a guide for using Paimon in Hive.&#xA;Version&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon currently supports Hive 3.1, 2.3, 2.2, 2.1 and 2.1-cdh-6.3.&#xA;Execution Engine&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon currently supports MR and Tez execution engine for Hive Read, and MR execution engine for Hive Write. Note If you use beeline, please restart the hive cluster.&#xA;Installation&#xD;#&#xD;Download the jar file with corresponding version.&#xA;Jar Hive 3.1 paimon-hive-connector-3.1-1.2.0.jar Hive 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trino</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/trino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/trino/</guid>
      <description>Trino&#xD;#&#xD;This documentation is a guide for using Paimon in Trino.&#xA;Version&#xD;#&#xD;Paimon currently supports Trino 440.&#xA;Filesystem&#xD;#&#xD;From version 0.8, Paimon share Trino filesystem for all actions, which means, you should config Trino filesystem before using trino-paimon. You can find information about how to config filesystems for Trino on Trino official website.&#xA;Preparing Paimon Jar File&#xD;#&#xD;Download&#xA;You can also manually build a bundled jar from the source code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amoro</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/amoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/ecosystem/amoro/</guid>
      <description>Apache Amoro With Paimon&#xD;#&#xD;Apache Amoro(incubating) is a Lakehouse management system built on open data lake formats. Working with compute engines including Flink, Spark, and Trino, Amoro brings pluggable and Table Maintenance features for a Lakehouse to provide out-of-the-box data warehouse experience, and helps data platforms or products easily build infra-decoupled, stream-and-batch-fused and lake-native architecture. AMS(Amoro Management Service) provides Lakehouse management features, like self-optimizing, data expiration, etc. It also provides a unified catalog service for all compute engines, which can also be combined with existing metadata services like HMS(Hive Metastore).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
